Barbara Wertheimer Collection of Audio Recordings 6144 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Barbara Wertheimer Collection of Audio Recordings
1973-1982
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wertheimer, Barbara
6144 AV
16.17 cubic feet
15.3 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
5819038
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 21, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 28, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Barbara Mayer Wertheimer (1926-September 23, 1983) was an American labor historian and labor organizer from the 1940s through the early 1980s.
From 1947 to 1948 Ms. Wertheimer was an organizer and acting education director for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. She worked briefly for the American Labor Education Service and then from 1961 to 1966 as a consultant for the New York State Division of Housing and Community Renewal. In 1966 Ms. Wertheimer joined the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University. While at Cornell she was a senior extension associate, director of the Trade Union Women's Studies program, and, from 1977 on, an associate professor and director of the Institute for Women and Work, which she cofounded. Ms. Wertheimer remained at Cornell until her death in 1983.
Ms. Wertheimer is well known for her monograph "We Were There: The Story of Working Women in America" (1977).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4015: Barbara Wertheimer Office Files 5729: Barbara Wertheimer Research Files 5736: Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files 5736 P: Barbara Wertheimer Photographs 6144: Barbara Wertheimer Additional Files
Women labor leaders; Wertheimer, Barbara
5819038
- Paulin Newman Lecture, 1975; 1 (Box 5)
  Scope and Contents
  February 10, 1975
- Notes from Pauline Newman Lecture, 1976; 2 (Box 5)
  May 19, 1976
- Pauline Newman Oral History by Barbara Wertheimer, 1976; 3 (Box 5)
  November 1976
- Catalog Cards for Audio Cassettes, 4 (Box 5)
  Incomplete
- Woman Alive! (Box 6)
- Rising of the Women (Box 7)
- Ann Shafer, June 1, 1974 (Box 8)
- Interview with Ann Shafer - June 1, 1974 (Box 9)
- Sexual harassment at work - Cornell - 3/18/1976 (Box 10)
- Cornell University, Rank File Women Interviewers -- 2/6/1973 #1 (Box 11)
- Cornell University, Rank File Women Interviewers - 2/6/1973 #2 (Box 12)
- Cornell University - Rank File Women Interviewers - 2/6/1973 #3 (Box 13)
- Women in Sweden - Swedish Info Office - 6/27/1974 (Box 14)
- Women in Sweden - Swedish Info Office -- 6/27/1974 (Box 15)
- In White Collar America - March 17, 1974 (Box 16)
- The Inheritance (Box 17)
- Woman's Place - September 8, 1973 (Box 18)
- Alex Haley - Roots -- June 8, 1973, Green Haven Correctional Facility, Stormville, NY, before a class of 80 inmates (Box 19)
  copy 2
- Alex Haley - Roots - June 8, 1973 - Green Haven Correctional Facility, Stormville, NY - Before a class of 80 inmates (Box 20)
  copy 1
- Oral History Interviews - Finley, Emma - June 11, 1976 (Box 21)
- Oral History Interviews - Skierski, Marie - June 11, 1976 (Box 22)
- Oral History Interviews - Sweeney, Florence - June 11, 1974 (Box 23)
- Three Women Alone (Box 24)
- We Were There - Lewis Hines (Box 25)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women #1 - Tribute to our Unions / Speaker: Bella Abzug (Box 26)
- Coalition of labor Union Women #2 - Tribute Conclusion, Vol. II - / Speaker Bella Abzug (Box 27)
- Cornell University - Rape - Muggers / Lucille Burriscamno, 2/26/1976 (Box 28)
- We the Women, March 17, 1974 (Box 29)
- Alice Cook - Govt. Support for Working Mothers (Box 30)
- Rossoff, Rose - 4/1/1976 (Box 31)
- Women in - WPIX - FM-- 6/30/1974 (Box 32)
- Huertz, Delores (Box 33)
- Women in Prison (Box 34)
- Women - White Collar Worker's / Barbara Wertheimer - 8/1/1980 (Box 35)
- Cornell Univ. - Interview of Graduates, March 1976 (Box 36)
- Cornell Univ. - Interview of Graduates, March 1976 (Box 37)
- The Perils of Pauline - 20th Century (Box 38)
- P. Foner - Black Women - 5/5/1976 (Box 39)
- Foner - Black Women, 19th Century - 5/5/1976 (Box 40)
- Cornell Univ. - TUWS - Graduation, June 28, 1976 (Box 41)
- Bea Schwartz, Storeworkers - 7/1/1974 (Box 42)
- Women Organizing Unions / Barbara Wertheimer - 9/17/1980 (Box 43)
- Joyce at 34 plus Fear Woman (Ghana) (Box 44)
- Cornell Student Interviews - 1976 (Box 45)
- August, Rebecca I - 1/29/1973 -- Sherna Gluck - FHRP 1973 (Box 46)
- August, Rebecca, II - 2/6/1973 -- Sherna Gluck. FHRP 1973 (Box 47)
- August, Rebecca III 3/19/1973 -- Sherna Gluck. FHRP. 1973 (Box 48)
- Executive Women in State Government - Midge Constanza (Box 49)
- Executive Women in State Government, May 26, 1977 (Box 50)
- Executive Women in State Government, may 26, 1977 (Box 51)
- Executive Women in State Government, May 26, 1977 (Box 52)
- Executive Women in State Government - May 26, 1977 (Box 53)
- Women as Third Party Neutrals - 1 (Box 54)
- Women as Third party Neutrals - 2 (Box 55)
- Women as Third Party Neutrals - 3 (Box 56)
- Women as Third Party Neutrals - 4 (Box 57)
- Women as Third Party Neutrals - 5 (Box 58)
- Cornell Univ. Institute for Education and Research on Women Work, Advisory Bd. Mtg. - April 20, 1978 (Box 59)
- The Origins of the National Labor Union and the Colored national Labor Union - Session Two (Box 60)
- Press Reception - Institute May 13, 1982 - M. Thomas (Box 61)
- Institute Advisory Bd. Mtg. - 5/2/1980 (Box 62)
- Institute Advisory Bd. Meeting - 5/2/1980 (Box 63)
- Working Women Law - April 15, 1978 -- Tape I (Box 64)
- Working Women the Law - April 15, 1978 -- Tape II (Box 65)
- 4/15/1978 -- tape III (Box 66)
- 4/15/1978 -- Tape IV (Box 67)
- Institute Board Mtg. - Mar. 8, 1979 (Box 68)
- Institute Board Mtg. - Mar. 8, 1979 (Box 69)
- Ex-Women in State Govt. - 11/9/1977 - tape I (Box 70)
- 11/9/1977 - tape II (Box 71)
- 11/9/1977 - tape III (Box 72)
- 11/9/1977 - tape IV (Box 73)
- 11/9/1977 - tape V (Box 74)
- 11/9/1977 - tape VI (Box 75)
- 11/9/1977 - tape VII (Box 76)
- International Dialogue 9/17/1979 - CLUW and Natl. Commission on W.W. (Box 77)
- US, Asia, Africa, Latin America (Box 78)
- Canada, Latin America (Box 79)
- Women at Work - On the Air (Box 80)
- Behavioral Sciences (Box 81)
- Conf.: Implementing Exec. Order - 6/8-9/1978 (Box 82)
- WWI Support Group - June (Box 83)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education Network (Box 84)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education network - tape II (Box 85)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education network - tape III (Box 86)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education network - tape IV (Box 87)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education network - Tape V (Box 88)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education network (Box 89)
- Cornell Univ. - Toward an education network (Box 90)
- Labor on the Air (Box 91)
- Women (Box 92)
- 4/21/1979 - Albany (Box 93)
- Panel dialog - 4/21/1979 (Box 94)
- Panel, cont. (Box 95)
- Advisory Board Vote - 6/30/1981 (Box 96)
- Advisory Board - 6/30/1981 (Box 97)
- Advisory Bd. Mtg. - 6/20/1981 (Box 98)
- First Nat'l. CLUW Conference - 3/1974 - WBAI - 6/18/1974 (Box 99)
- Cornell - NYSSILR - Women the International World of Work - I II (Box 100)
- Cornell - NYSSILR - Women the International World of Work - III IV (Box 101)
- Cornell - NYSSILR - Women the International World of Work - V (Box 102)
- Cornell - NYSSILR - Women the International World of Work - VII, VIII (Box 103)
- Cornell - NYSSILR - Women the International World of Work - IX-X (Box 104)
- Cornell U. - TUWS - Focus on Worker Unionists - tape I (Box 105)
- Morning Panel - Disc. -- 11/4/1974 - tape II (Box 106)
- Workshop II con't. final summary - Tape III (Box 107)
- Cornell - TUWS - Focus on Women Unionists - Workshop I - 11/14/1974 (Box 108)
- Workshop II, 11/14/1974 - Focus on Women Unionists (Box 109)
- Cornell Univ. - N.Y. Trade Union Women's Conf. (Box 110)
- N.Y. Trade Union Women's Conf. - Edited Proceedings - 1/19/1974 (Box 111)
- Cornell Univ. - NYSSILR - TUWS - NY Trade Union Women's Conference (Box 112)
- Cornell Univ. - NYSSILR - TUWS - NY Trade Union Women's Conference - Tape 1A (Box 113)
- Cornell Univ. - NYSSILR - TUWS - NY Trade Union Women's Conference - #3 (Box 114)
- Cornell Univ. NYSSILR - Trade Union Women's Studies - First NY Trade Union Women's Conference #4 (Box 115)
- De Briefing for workshop leaders, January 23, 1974 (Box 116)
- Women in American Labor History - Session I (Box 117)
- Women in American Labor History - Session II (Box 118)
- Women in American Labor History - Session II (Box 119)
- Women in American Labor History - Session III (Box 120)
- Women in American Labor History - Session III (Box 121)
- Women in American Labor History - Session 4 5 (Box 122)
- Women in American Labor History - Session IV (Box 123)
- Women in American Labor History - Session VII (Box 124)
- Women in American Labor History - Session 5 (Box 125)
- Women in American Labor History - Session VI (Box 126)
- Grace Weiner on Sweat Shops (Box 127)
- Cornell Univ. - TUWS - Women in American Labor History - Session VI - Reports Newman Tapes (Box 128)
- Women in American Labor History - VI - Newman (Box 129)
- Women in American Labor History #7 (Box 130)
- Women in Labor history, Reports, Session VIII, Class II and I (Box 131)
- Women in American Labor History - Session 12 (Box 132)
- Women in American Labor History - Session 12 (Box 133)
- Cornell Univ. - NYSSILR - Institute for Education Research on Women Work, Mathematics Teacher Training, March 10, 1978 (Box 134)
- Cornell Univ. - NYSSILR - Institute for Education Research on Women and Work, Mathematics Teacher Training, March 10, 1978 (Box 135)
- Women in American Labor History - Session V- Sojourner Truth (Box 136)
- Women in American Labor History - Session V- Sojourner Truth - tape 2 (Box 137)